OFGEHA GELANA

AI RESEARCHER AND BACKEND DEVELOPER

CONTACT

- +251935070773
- ✓ ofgehagelana2019@gmail.com
- Addis Ababa, Ethiopia
- www.ofge.com
- in www.linkedin.com/in/ofgeha-gelana

EDUCATION

2019 - 2023 ASTU UNIVERSITY

- Computer Science and Engineering
- Bachelor of Science
- GPA: 3.8 / 4.0

SKILLS

- Python
- Django Framework
- Machine Learning
- RESTful API Development
- Agile Methodologies
- Version Control (Git)
- Teamwork
- Effective Communication

LANGUAGES

- English (Fluent)
- Amharic(Fluent)
- Oromo(Fluent)

PROFILE

Eager Python Django developer with four years exploiting model-template-view architectural pattern of Django framework to shorten development times and reduce design costs. Specializes in creating accessible, data-driven web assets with AI integration. Keen to apply expansive development knowledge to deliver fast, efficient Healthcare management system projects.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Ethiopian Artificial Intelligence Institution 2023 - PRESENT

AI Researcher and developer

- Designs and implements AI software solutions, integrating ML models into scalable apps for efficiency.
- Develops AI products, using ML frameworks like TensorFlow, PyTorch, ensuring robustness.
- Engineers AI infrastructure, deploying ML models in production, ensuring reliability and scalability.

Information Network Security Agency 2022 - 2023 Python Django Developer (Intern II)

- Leads projects, architects scalable solutions, and implements best practices for performance and security.
- Designs robust backend systems with Django, RESTful APIs, and database optimizations for efficient data handling.
- Contributes to complex Django apps, collaborates crossfunctionally, delivering high-quality using Agile.

EthioTelecom

Cybersecurity Engineer (Intern I)

o retecom

2021 - 2022

- Implements and manages security solutions to protect networks and systems from cyber threats.
- Manages security operations, monitors for security incidents, and responds to incidents as needed.

CERTIFICATIONS

Python	Coursera
Data Science	Coursera
Django	Coursera
Java	Coursera
GitHub	Udemy

OFGEHA GELANA

AI RESEARCHER AND BACKEND DEVELOPER

CONTACT

+251935070773

✓ ofgehagelana2019@gmail.com

Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

www.ofge.com

www.ofge.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ofgeha-gelana

EDUCATION

2019 - 2023 ASTU UNIVERSITY

- Computer Science and Engineering
- Bachelor of Science
- GPA: 3.8 / 4.0

SKILLS

- Python
- Django Framework
- Machine Learning
- RESTful API Development
- Agile Methodologies
- Version Control (Git)
- Teamwork
- Effective Communication

LANGUAGES

- English (Fluent)
- Amharic(Fluent)
- Oromo(Fluent)

PROFILE

Eager Python Django developer with four years exploiting modeltemplate-view architectural pattern of Django framework to shorten development times and reduce design costs. Specializes in creating accessible, data-driven web assets with AI integration. Keen to apply expansive development knowledge to deliver fast, efficient Healthcare management system projects.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Ethiopian Artificial Intelligence Institution 2023 - PRESENT

AI Researcher and developer

- Designs and implements AI software solutions, integrating ML models into scalable apps for efficiency.
- Develops AI products, using ML frameworks like TensorFlow, PyTorch, ensuring robustness.
- Engineers AI infrastructure, deploying ML models in production, ensuring reliability and scalability.

Information Network Security Agency 2022 - 2023 Python Django Developer (Intern II)

- Leads projects, architects scalable solutions, and implements best practices for performance and security.
- Designs robust backend systems with Django, RESTful APIs, and database optimizations for efficient data handling.
- Contributes to complex Django apps, collaborates crossfunctionally, delivering high-quality using Agile.

EthioTelecom 2021 - 2022

Cybersecurity Engineer (Intern I)

- Implements and manages security solutions to protect networks and systems from cyber threats.
- Manages security operations, monitors for security incidents, and responds to incidents as needed.

CERTIFICATIONS

Python	Coursera
Data Science	Coursera
Django	Coursera
Java	Coursera
GitHub	Udemy